All right, I think I'll just talk about the
dynamic frame now, instead of in
the deep dive, because we are already on this particular code here.
As I said before, dynamic frame is a Glue concept. Okay?
Now, you learned about Spark data frames in the PySpark Skill
Booster course. I mean, if you have not seen that, you, you will learn the Spark
data frames in the PySpark Skill Booster course.
And you need to know something, that Glue
is based on the
open source Spark. And also note that Glue is n- that Glue dynamic
frame is not same as that of the PySpark data frame,
okay? The only use case I have come across so far of a
dynamic frame is this: to be able to read the
data object, okay, which has been cataloged already, which has
been crawled upon, and a table has been created in
the Glue catalog. There are other advantages to Glue
dynamic frames as per the documentation, but I have not come
across other use cases so far. So this one use case should
be sufficient if you are asked about the difference
between a dynamic frame and a Spark data frame.
One more thing you have to understand is that to be able to continue with our
Spark coding, PySpark-based coding, we need to
convert the dynamic frame to a regular Spark data
frame using the to_df
method. So this piece of code here, it creates a dynamic
frame by looking at the catalog, database, and table name.
And of course, as I said, you have to provide the transformation context here for
the Glue bookmark to work. And after you have created the
dynamic frame, the immi- immediate step should be to convert the
dynamic frame to a Spark data frame so that
you can continue using your PySpark-based
code. This is the method we typically follow
for us to leverage our PySpark knowledge.
If we do not convert the Glue dynamic frame to a
Spark data frame, we will be restricted to use the
Glue-based Spark coding. As I said, Glue
is based on Spark, so you can also
work using Glue Spark, which is slightly different than the
open source Apache Spark-based APIs.
Okay, I'll repeat the whole thing so that it's not confusing.
Glue is based on the open source Apache Spark.
You have learned PySpark in the Skill Booster course.
If not, you will learn that over there.
It'll hardly take a couple hours. When you read
a catalog object, the table that has been
crawled and cataloged in the Glue catalog, using this
construct you see here,
GlueContext.create_dynamic_frame_from_catalog, you will create a
dynamic frame, which is a Glue-specific thing.
And in Spark, we have something called a Spark data
frame. That is different than the dynamic frame, and the use
case of using a dynamic frame is for enabling
the Glue bookmarks. And the requirements
for enabling the bookmarks are a few things which I have discussed in
the previous video. And lastly, you can continue working on the
dynamic frame using the Glue Spark, which is an extension
of Apache Spark. But if you are somebody who's
learning PySpark, or somebody who already knows PySpark, you can
leverage your PySpark knowledge by converting
the Glue dynamic frame to a Spark data frame
using the to_data_frame method. So on the dynamic frame, you apply the
to_data_frame.
This will return a Spark data frame, and you can then continue
using the PySpark APIs instead of
the Glue Spark APIs. I hope this is clear.
This is a very important thing. Let me know in a comment below what you have
understood, so that I know that you have internalized
this concept. I'll talk to you soon in the next
video.